LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/atul-kumar-51548095/

ATUL KUMAR

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Experienced Java Developer with over 4 years in building, testing and deploying scalable and modular software products. Organised and hardworking team player. Uses strong interpersonal skills to work well with internal and external stakeholders to meet project technical requirements.

WORK HISTORY

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER 06/2023 to Current

American Express, Gurgaon, India

- Project Cornerstone portal provides access to data lake from which different internal teams can subscribe to data, or publish new data.
- Tech stack java, springboot, microservices, big-data, hibernate/JPA, graphQL, google-cloud.
- Worked with product managers to define software requirements and project scopes accurately.
- Architected and developed complex software solutions, meeting project specifications and deadlines.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER 01/2022 to 06/2023

Amdocs, Gurgaon, India

- Project Charter O2A provides fault management system which uses spark-Kafka pipeline
 to fetch failed orders from source database(oracle), apply transformations on data and
 saves to target database(Cassandra). The target database is further processed to generate
 reports and provides facility to handle these orders via automation or manual steps.
- Tech stack java, springboot, microservices, ETL pipeline, Spark, Kafka, Cassandra DB, Oracle DB, Docker, Kubernetes.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER 04/2021 to 12/2021

Glaucus Logistics, Delhi, India

- Project Glaucus Maven the combination of OMS, WMS & FMS. OMS is the order management system. FMS is the Fleet Management system and WMS is the warehouse management System. Worked on shopify integration, junit test cases, api development and fixing defects during my tenure here.
- Tech stack java, springboot, MySQL, Hibernate/JPA, Microservices, ActiveMQ, Flutter
- Adapted to different languages and technologies based on project requirements.

SOFTWARE ENGINEER 03/2020 to 03/2021

V3 Smart Technologies Pte Ltd, New Delhi, India

- Project FMS used for tracking and viewing status of Vehicles and Filed Workers, generating reports of their activities. Worked as full stack developer during my tenure here.
 Daily activities include creating JSP pages, backend APIs creation, jUnit test cases.
- Tech stack java, spring MVC, JSP, HTML/CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap.

INTERNSHIPS

• Computer science expert at Evelyn Learning Systems Pvt Ltd from 08/2019 to 12/2019

SKILLS

- Java 8
- Talend
- SpringBoot

AWS (EC2)

- ETL Spark-Kafka
- Microservices
- pipeline
- Hibernate/JPA
- Kubernetes/Docker
- GCP (Pub-sub API)
- FlutterJSP HTML/CSS jQuery

EDUCATION

Galgotias University, Greater Noida, Uttar Pradesh **Master of Technology**, Computer science engineering, 08/2018 to 07/2020

- Research paper Corrective Suggestions to Exercise Performed at Home by Physiotherapy Patients using Motion Analysis
- Publication IJRTE

Guru Gobin Singh Indraprastha University, India

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer science engineering, 08/2012 to 05/2016

LANGUAGES

English:

Fluent